<WA council="1">
<RESOLUTION><CATEGORY>Repeal</CATEGORY>
<COAUTHOR>
<N>the_ice_states</N>
<N>prov</N>
</COAUTHOR>
<CREATED>1767034690</CREATED>
<DESC><![CDATA[The World Assembly,

Noting the purpose of GAR #546 to lift restrictions upon minority groups from donating blood, while increasing the efficiency of blood donation to improve medical treatment,

However, displeased by these flaws in the resolution&#39;s execution:
[list][*]The target&#39;s failure to effectively prevent discrimination in blood donation, as while it requires that members of minorities be allowed to donate, it still allows the immediate discarding of a minority donor&#39;s blood due to the donor belonging to said minority group.


[*]Section 4 declaring categorically that &quot;it shall be considered a criminal offense to knowingly attempt to donate unsafe blood&quot; includes donation for research, where it is irrelevant whether the blood is safe for transfusions or not. This pointlessly hinders research regarding blood-borne illnesses by making it difficult to obtain blood carrying those illnesses.


[*]Section 5, which states, &#147;existing scientific committees created by this body shall be utilized to share information related to blood-borne illnesses and blood donation across member states, as to mitigate any risk of contaminated blood&#148;, does not include any restrictions or prevention of the sharing of private information of individuals that may possess a blood borne illness, thus infringing on the right of any person to not have their private information disclosed. 
 

[*]The target is largely superfluous under existing laws and does not require replacement. GAR #546 states nearly identical principles to [url=https://www.nationstates.net/page=WA_past_resolution/id=457/council=1]GAR #457[/url], which already addresses discrimination based on sexuality, implicitly including blood donation. Likewise, [url=https://www.nationstates.net/page=WA_past_resolution/id=217/council=1]GAR #217[/url] already declares that &#147;prospective donors of biomedical tissues shall not be discriminated against without a valid medical rationale&#148;.[/list]
Asserting that this repeal will relieve unnecessary burdens upon member states, noting that similar resolutions can function without needing to be duplicated &#150; often ineffectively &#150; by the target,

Hereby repeals GAR #546, [url=https://www.nationstates.net/page=WA_past_resolution/id=546/council=1]Blood Donation Safety and Equality Act[/url]&#148;.

]]></DESC>
<ID>general_tn_1767034690</ID>
<NAME>Repeal &quot;Blood Donation Safety and Equality Act&quot;</NAME>
<OPTION>893</OPTION>
<PROMOTED>1771520403</PROMOTED>
<PROPOSED_BY>general_tn</PROPOSED_BY>
<TOTAL_NATIONS_AGAINST>16</TOTAL_NATIONS_AGAINST>
<TOTAL_NATIONS_FOR>52</TOTAL_NATIONS_FOR>
<TOTAL_VOTES_AGAINST>17</TOTAL_VOTES_AGAINST>
<TOTAL_VOTES_FOR>912</TOTAL_VOTES_FOR>
<VOTES_AGAINST><N>malaya_communism</N>
<N>merpiana</N>
<N>xjeff</N>
<N>beanastan</N>
<N>newfoundland_and_gaspesie</N>
<N>luccaa</N>
<N>skelleftella</N>
<N>knootoss</N>
<N>imperial_northern_states</N>
<N>aguyje-yvy</N>
<N>elucubria</N>
<N>nasa_space_program</N>
<N>nezgzarp</N>
<N>wattsland</N>
<N>urlaska</N>
<N>qing_zhaodao</N></VOTES_AGAINST>
<VOTES_FOR><N>oseao</N>
<N>new_united_communist_front_of_ruzonya</N>
<N>forfishing</N>
<N>landbang_rkipo_islands</N>
<N>spheniscidae_islands</N>
<N>cyvin</N>
<N>vuilla</N>
<N>art_landia</N>
<N>true_green_an_gold_australia</N>
<N>democratic_wer</N>
<N>hergonia</N>
<N>namante</N>
<N>itani</N>
<N>bhang_bhang_duc</N>
<N>the_dark_aether</N>
<N>achias</N>
<N>random_island_in_the_arctic</N>
<N>derkma</N>
<N>humanlonia</N>
<N>paladoma</N>
<N>mjau</N>
<N>cathendale</N>
<N>maraffe</N>
<N>horschaia</N>
<N>greater_britannian_realm</N>
<N>new_aquitaine</N>
<N>erstavik</N>
<N>unified-korea</N>
<N>digital_drovakia</N>
<N>quesbia</N>
<N>moduland</N>
<N>aeryn</N>
<N>foxy</N>
<N>hobura</N>
<N>austrasul</N>
<N>socialist_union_of_alisa_mikhailovna</N>
<N>chernistiv</N>
<N>nazarionia</N>
<N>the_central_islands</N>
<N>zeu</N>
<N>inco</N>
<N>differences-in-differences</N>
<N>femboy_skye</N>
<N>eieryn</N>
<N>norwegian_forest_cat</N>
<N>the_peoples_commonwealth_of_ardentia</N>
<N>gagium</N>
<N>the_freakin_guardians_of_the_galaxy</N>
<N>nordgardia</N>
<N>theroria</N>
<N>blodenil</N>
<N>reasonable_union</N></VOTES_FOR>
</RESOLUTION>
</WA>
