<WA council="1">
<RESOLUTION><CATEGORY>Civil Rights</CATEGORY>
<COAUTHOR>
<N>mar_teret</N>
<N>mlgdogeland</N>
</COAUTHOR>
<CREATED>1772393940</CREATED>
<DESC><![CDATA[The General Assembly,

Recognising a responsibility to protect prisoners of war,

Desiring to comprehensively protect prisoners of war in member nations,

Hereby:

[list=1][*]Defines, for the purposes of this resolution, &quot;prisoner of war&quot;, henceforth referred to as &quot;POW&quot;, as any member of an armed service who has been captured by an opposing force.


[*]Bans the following practices:
[list=a][*]The capture and internment of civilians by any military or nation, without reasonable suspicion of a crime or proof thereof, or unless there is a legal and substantiated warrant for arrest or a provable connection to an ongoing criminal proceeding,
[*]The censorship of communication between POWs, and those they communicate to, where there is no demonstrable threat to security,
[*]The application of corporal punishment, or any other form of torture, upon POWs,
[*]The killing of POWs, 
[*]The coercion of information from POWs, and
[*]The use of POWs for any form of forced labor.[/list]

[*]Requires that member nations provide the following to all POWs, regardless of any immutable distinguishing factor: 
[list=a][*]Sustenance and water sufficient to sustain life and healthy nutrition, 
[*]Facilities for living which are clean, adequately lit and heated, and protected from typical weather conditions,
[*]Facilities and resources required to maintain basic hygiene,
[*]Proper clothing,
[*]Methods for periodical communication to their homeland, and
[*]Any other facilities necessary to carry out the prior requirements.[/list]

[*]Allows member nations to engage in POW exchanges in wartime. All POWs in wartime exchanges must be safely transported to the point of exchange. Member nations should take necessary precautions to ensure their POWs&#39; safety during transport as much as reasonably possible.

[*]Stipulates that all POWs must be released and returned upon the end of the respective war, except where continued detention is strictly necessary for a defined and lawful criminal process, and such detention shall be limited in duration to that which is reasonably required for investigation or adjudication.

[*]Stipulates that, if a POW is to die in captivity, that the remains are protected from desecration and properly returned to the family of the POW or the military they served, whichever is present.[/list]]]></DESC>
<ID>untecna_1772393940</ID>
<NAME>Protecting Wartime Internees</NAME>
<OPTION>0</OPTION>
<PROMOTED>1777435204</PROMOTED>
<PROPOSED_BY>untecna</PROPOSED_BY>
<TOTAL_NATIONS_AGAINST>0</TOTAL_NATIONS_AGAINST>
<TOTAL_NATIONS_FOR>1</TOTAL_NATIONS_FOR>
<TOTAL_VOTES_AGAINST>0</TOTAL_VOTES_AGAINST>
<TOTAL_VOTES_FOR>110</TOTAL_VOTES_FOR>
<VOTES_AGAINST></VOTES_AGAINST>
<VOTES_FOR><N>oseao</N></VOTES_FOR>
</RESOLUTION>
</WA>
